# **Charles Wu**

#### **UX** Engineer

# Summary

A versatile user-experience designer & developer. Adept in converting user needs into product requirements, with project analysis skills. Efficient at creating designs that translate into tangible results, through the means of prototypes, animation, and code.

# **Experience**

### **UX Engineer, Highline Beta**

Jul 2018 - Jun 2019

- Tested and deployed new features for internal and external projects, applying lean methodologies
- Explored and validated novel industry problems for new ventures
- Synthesized and validated solutions for the aforementioned problems

#### Sr UX Developer, CareerJSM

Sep 2016 - Apr 2018

- Designed features, wireframes, mockups, and prototypes for stakeholders, presenting new features
- Audited and implemented code for accessibility, responsiveness, and localization compatibility
- Conducted user testing and interviews iteratively for feature releases
- Mentored team members and led the company in best UX practices

#### **UX** Developer, Dive Networks

Aug 2015 - Jul 2016

- Optimized content for web and TV mediums, factoring in content size, speed, and viewer distance
- Created user personas and use-cases to enhance functionality and usability for target audiences
- Hosted company UX training sessions to enhance product usability and accessibility
- Developed an automation script to detect and flag visual differences

#### **UX Developer, Crowd Curio**

Jan 2015 - Jun 2015

- Researched and prototyped a citizen-science based platform
- Improved user engagement by testing and optimizing different layouts and through added gamification elements
- Designed information architecture maps, wireframes, and website, created with HTML/CSS/JS

### Education

# Bachelors of Applied Science, University of Waterloo

2015

# Systems Design Engineering, Option in Management Science

### Contact

charleswu.ca

M hi@charleswu.ca

(+1) 647-767-6126

# **UX Skills**

**Product Strategy** User Research Information Architecture Design Interaction Design Prototyping

Web Accessibility (WCAG 2.0)

## **Dev Skills**

**HTML** CSS (SCSS, BEM) JS (React, Ember) Python Git

### Tools

Figma Sketch Invision Axure Illutsrator, Photoshop, After Effects VSCode, Sublime, CLI

#### Hobbies & Interests

Rock climbing, bouldering **Photography** Video games Volleyball Cycling Whiskey, Bourbon, Scotch